第 16 章：鼻辅音。用舌头阻断气流，并让气流
Chapter 16. Nasal consonants. Block the air with your tongue and release it
通过鼻子释放。现在我们转向三个声音从鼻腔出来的辅音。
through your nose. We now turn to the three consonants whose sounds come out
M、N 和 NG 组合。它们都有一个共同点：
through the nose. M, N, and the NG combination. They each have one thing in
它们的声音会在口腔里的三个位置之一被阻断。
common. Their sound is blocked in the mouth in one of three locations. Two of
其中两个，N 和 NG，像 R 一样甚至看不见，所以很难捕捉。M 是
them, N and NG, you can't even see, as with R, so they're hard to pick up on. M is the
最容易、最明显，像 B。双唇合上，气流出不去，
easiest and most obvious, like b. The lips come together and the air can't get out so
只好从鼻子出来。N 的位置类似 T，但完全不能
it has to come through the nose. N is in a position similar to t, but it can't be at
紧张；它必须完全放松，充满整个口腔，并接触
all tense. It has to be completely relaxed, filling the whole mouth, touching
所有牙齿内侧，让气流除了从鼻子出去之外没有别的出口。
the insides of all the teeth, leaving no room for the air to escape except by the
NG 在喉咙后部，位置对应 G；舌背向后顶住，
nose. NG is back in the throat with G. The back of the tongue presses back and again
气流同样从鼻子出来。
the air comes out through the nose.